Finding Aid for the Kim Kralj papers 1985-1991 LSC.2157
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kim Kralj papers
1974-1991
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kralj, Kim
LSC.2157
2.4 Linear Feet (6 document boxes)
Kim Kralj is a community activist and art dealer based primarily in Los Angeles, California. The collection consists primarily of agendas, minutes, subject files, and general notes of action regarding West Hollywood's recognition and promotion of its gay and lesbian citizens, including information about the Gay and Lesbian Task Force and the Lesbian and Gay Advisory Committee on which Kralj served.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Kim Kralj, 1991. This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973479183606533
Biography
Kim Kralj is an art dealer, human services commissioner, and community activist primarily based in Los Angeles, California. She served on the West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force and the West Hollywood Lesbian and Gay Advisory Board. The West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force was the precursor to the present West Hollywood Gay and Lesbian Advisory Board, and served as a liaison between residents, police, and city council. In addition to her work with the Task Force, Kralj also served as the June Mazer Lesbian Archives board president.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of agendas, minutes, subject files, and general notes of action regarding West Hollywood's recognition and promotion of its gay and lesbian citizens, including information about the Gay and Lesbian Task Force and the Lesbian and Gay Advisory Committee on which Kralj served.
Organization and Arrangement
The materials were grouped by project and arranged into the following series:
Series 1: West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force
Series 2: Sheriff's Conference Committee
Series 3: Organizing, programming, and subject files
Related Material
Lesbian Visibility Week records
Ivy Bottini papers
Sallie M. Fiske Papers and Photographs
ACT UP/Los Angeles records
West Hollywood Gay and Lesbian Task Force -- Archives.; Gay rights.; West Hollywood (Calif.); University of California, Los Angeles. Library; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA; Kralj, Kim -- Archives
- Series 1: West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1986-1991
  Scope and Content
  Contains the minutes, agendas, reports, and supporting material related to and covered in meetings held by the West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force between January 1988 and July 1991. The West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force was the precursor to the present West Hollywood Gay and Lesbian Advisory Board and served as a liaison between residents, police, and city council.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force: General, circa 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Content note
    Contains Kim Kralj's personal notes on West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force public hearings, a member contact list, undated committee recommendations, and two handbooks on human services.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1987 February - 1988 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1987 July - 1988 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1986 November - 1988 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1987 January - 1988 April (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    Includes West Hollywood General Plan Household Survey Results and a Gay/Lesbian Survey.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes Social Service Programs review.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 August (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    Includes a law enforcement agreement for the West Hollywood Christopher Street West Parade, rough draft of gay/lesbian questionnaire, ballot initiatives, and a Child Care Policy Report.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 September (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 October (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains the minutes, agendas, reports, and supporting material related to and covered in meetings held by the West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force in October 1988.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1988 December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes the Department of Human Services' 90 Day Work Plans.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 February (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes the Possible Annual Plan for 1989/1990, and a briefing paper on Proposition 99.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 March (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes the midyear agency evaluations and self assessments of the Social Services agencies contracted with the city.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 April (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes AIDS agenda items and 1988-1989 Workplan Accomplishments.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 May (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 May - 1989 June (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes article on police brutality, AIDS related legislation, documents on the Warming Center food program, and a Park Ranger Report.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 July (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 August (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1987 May - 1989 September (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes a Needle Exchange Program Report, and a summary of pending legislation.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1989 October (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 February (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 April (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Contains a Community Needs Assessment Report.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 June (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 October (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Includes 1990-1991 Social Services Orientation Agenda.
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 November (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1990 December (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1991 March (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1991 April (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1991 June (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Task Force, 1991July (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series 2: West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Sheriff's Conference Committee, 1985-1990
  Contains minutes, reports, correspondence, complaints of harrassment, articles, memos, and other records related to the West Hollywood Gay/Lesbian Sheriff's Conference Committee.
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: Meetings, 1988 January - 1990 May (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: West Hollywood Sheriff's contract renewal, 1985 May - 1985 June (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: Sheriff's Department recruitment, 1988 March - 1989 June (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: ACT UP harassment, 1989 July - 1989 October (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: San Francisco Office of Citizen's Complaints, 1987 July - 1989 October (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: Department correspondence, 1988 January - 1989 September (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sheriff's Conference Committee: International Association for Civilian Oversight of Law Enforcement (IACOLE), 1989 September (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series 3: Organizing, programming, and subject files, 1974 - 1991
  Contains correspondence, articles, legislation, and other records documenting other committee work and programming in which Kim Kralj was involved, including Lesbian Visibility Week and the West Hollywood City Council.
  - Lesbian and Gay Advisory Council, 1989 February - 1991 March (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
    Contains the minutes, notes, correspondences and articles of topic related to the Lesbian and Gay Advisory Council meetings in 1989.
  - Lesbian Visibility Week, 1990 February - 1991 July (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    Contains a list of subcommittee participants, calendar events, revenue information, news articles, meeting information and correspondences related to the 1990 Lesbian Visibility Week in West Hollywood.
    Contains calendar events, news articles, meeting information and correspondences related to the 1991 Lesbian Visibility Week in West Hollywood.
  - Women's Issues Task Force, 1987 December - 1988 October (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Contains press releases, group recommendations, and notes regarding the Women's Issues Task Force.
  - Women's History Month, circa 1990 - 1991 March; Printed documents, flyers (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Contains press releases, flyers and event lists of activities related to Women's History Month.
  - West Hollywood City Council, 1988 September - 1991 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Contains press releases, notes, correspondences, assessments and reports related to West Hollywood City Council meetings and activities.
  - Decriminalization of prostitution: papers and correspondence, 1984 July - 1990 October; Printed documents (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Contains correspondences, policies, profiles, news articles, an information sheet from the National Organization for Women (NOW) entitled "Prostitution is a Feminist Issue," and position papers related to prostitution legislation and decriminalization.
  - Decriminalization of prostitution: legislation and publications, circa 1974-1990; Legal briefs, handbooks (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
    Contains the following publications: "Commercial Sex and the Rights of the Person: A Moral Argument for the Decriminalization of Prostitution" by David Richards, an issue of Truth Seeker including the article "Prostitution and the Criminal Justice System" by Norma Jean Almodovar, "Prostitutes Prevent AIDS: A Manual for Health Educators" by Priscilla Alexander, "Prostitution: A Feminist Analysis" by Belinda Cooper, "Police Corruption: A Sociological Perspective" edited by Lawrence W. Sherman, "Working on Prostitution" by Priscilla Alexander, "The Highest Paying Customers: America's Cities and the Costs of Prostitution Control" by Julie Pearl, "The Criminalization of the AIDS Epidemic" (National Lawyers Guild Aids Network), "AIDS and Intravenous Drug Use" edited by Don C. DesJarlais, "Should Prostitution Be Legalized?" by Charles Halleck, "What Laws Should Govern Prostitution?" New York committee report, and "AIDS, Prostitution and the Use of Historical Stereotypes to Legislate Sexuality" by Beth Bergman.
  - Articles and West Hollywood City Plan, 1987 September - 1988 June; Printed documents (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    Contains "Press, Politics and Polls," articles from the San Francisco Sentinel, and the City of West Hollywood General Plan book.
  - Memorabilia, 1988; Pin (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Contains Kim Kralj's admission pass pin to the 1988 National Lesbian Rights Conference in San Diego, California.